One man's search for amorous requital in a land where the sun never sets.
Twilight of the Ice Nymphs is a fantasy, romance,
comedy film directed by Guy Maddin.
Set in a blazing land where the sun ceaselessly shines, this
dramatic fantasy examines love’s darker aspects.
Peter Glahn (uncredited), played by Nigel Whitmey.
Juliana Kossel, played by Pascale Bussières.
Amelia Glahn, played by Shelley Duvall.
Cain Ball, played by Frank Gorshin.
Zephyr Eccles, played by Alice Krige.
Dr. Issac Solti, played by R.H. Thomson.
Twilight of the Ice Nymphs is a 1997 fantasy
romance film directed by Guy Maddin.
The screenplay was written by George Toles and inspired by the novel Pan (1894) by Knut Hamsun, with an
additional literary touchstones being the short story "La Vénus d'Ille" (1837) by Prosper Mérimée.
Twilight of the Ice Nymphs was Maddin's second feature film in colour
and his first shot in 35 mm, on a budget of $1.5 million.
As seen in Noam Gonick's documentary Waiting for Twilight, Maddin was dissatisfied with
the filmmaking process due to creative interference from his producers.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.